





Maintenance, Production support (Java, J2EE, JPA, Hibernate, Webservices (REST Full), Spring framework, Springboot, microservices, pivotal cloud, redis cache, rabbit MQ)

Current Designation: Technical Manager Total Experience: 13 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Current Company: Birlasoft Notice Period: 3 Months

Current Location: Hyderabad / Secunderabad Highest Degree: MCA [Computers]

Pref. Location: Hyderabad

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Project Mgr-IT/Software

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Married

 $\label{lem:condition} Key Skills: java, j2ee, jpa, hibernate, spring framework, spring boot, Microservices, Web Services, Rest, Maven, JUnit, GIT, bitbucket, MySQL, pivotal cloud fundry, Jenkins, Sonar, Continuous Services, Rest, Maven, JUnit, GIT, bitbucket, MySQL, pivotal cloud fundry, Jenkins, Sonar, Continuous Services, Rest, Maven, JUnit, GIT, bitbucket, MySQL, pivotal cloud fundry, Jenkins, Sonar, Continuous Services, Rest, Mayen, Junit, GIT, bitbucket, MySQL, pivotal cloud fundry, Jenkins, Sonar, Continuous Services, Rest, Mayen, Junit, GIT, bitbucket, MySQL, pivotal cloud fundry, Jenkins, Sonar, Continuous Services, Rest, Mayen, Junit, GIT, bitbucket, MySQL, pivotal cloud fundry, Jenkins, Sonar, Continuous Services, Rest, Mayen, Junit, GIT, bitbucket, MySQL, pivotal cloud fundry, Jenkins, Sonar, Continuous Services, Rest, Mayen, Junit, GIT, bitbucket, MySQL, pivotal cloud fundry, Jenkins, Sonar, Continuous Services, Rest, Mayen, Junit, GIT, bitbucket, MySQL, pivotal cloud fundry, Jenkins, Sonar, Continuous Services, Rest, Mayen, MySQL, pivotal cloud fundry, Jenkins, Sonar, Continuous Services, Rest, MySQL, pivotal cloud fundry, Jenkins, Rest, MySQL, pivotal cloud fundry, Rest, MySQL, pivotal cloud fundry, Rest, MySQL, pivotal cloud fundry, Rest, MySQL, pivotal cloud f$ 

Integration, Nexus, Continuous Delivery, Fortify, spring cloud

Verified : Phone Number | Email - id

Last Modified: 18-Jan-21 Last Modified: 18-Jan-21

Jump to Section

Work Experience | Education | IT Skills

## **Summary**

Overall 13 years of experience as a developer, Tech Lead and technical manager with scrum in Enterprise - level implementation of the Software Development Life-Cycle (SDLC), including Architecture, Functional and Technical design, Development, Implementation and Support.

Expertise in Java, J2EE, Springs Core, Spring M/C, Spring Boot, Hibernate, Web Services (REST API) and microservices. Solid experience in implementing applications for global operations in diverse industries using Design Patterns. Diverse experience utilizing tools on Micro services architecture applications using Spring Boot, Spring Cloud config Strong experience in Application Servers like Glassfish and Tomcat server,

Spring boot, microservices, Spring cloud, pcf, Jenkins, Maven, git, redis cache, rabbit MQ, microservices, spring

## **Work Experience**

Birlasoft as Technical Manager Feb 2019 to Till Date

Technical Manager

Accenture Services Pvt Ltd as Technical Lead -Java, J2EE

Jun 2006 to Jun 2015

Role: Service Delivery Lead:

Responsible for IT Services delivery (Application Development, Enhancements and support) involvolved in development and Enhancement of the web applications using Java, J2EE, Spring M/C, Hibernate technologies and REST services.

Quality, Process adherence & process improvement by reviewing the integrated service level codes. worked for BMW Germany, Lloyd's bank UK and General Motors US

Portland technologies as Associate Software Engineer May 2004 to May 2006

java developer

^ Back to Top

## **Education**

UG: B.Sc (Maths) from Acharya Nagarjuna University, Hyderabad in 2000

PG: MCA (Computers) from Acharya Nagarjuna University, Hyderabad in 2004

# **Important**

 Using Free CV Search you have access to featured candidate profiles of Naukri. You can browse through the profiles and email the candidates of your choice directly using the email option provided. To prevent misuse of candidate information, contact details and attached resume of the candidates have been withheld

## IT Skills

Skill Name	Version Last Used	Experience
JAVA, J2EE		
JDBC, Servlets, JSP, JMS, JPA, JTA		
Hibernate		
Rest Full WebServices		
SQL		
Microservices, pcf, rabbitmq,redis cache		
Spring Boot, Spring Framework		

^ Back to Top

# Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak	
English	Proficient	✓	✓	✓	

^ Back to Top

## **Affirmative Action**

## **Work Authorization**

Category: General Job Type: Permanent

Physically Challenged: No Employment Status: Full time

^ Back to Top

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQ's - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICIClcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQs - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICIClcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.